Cedric HARTLAND

PhD, Senior Software Engineer, Scrum Master AI - Back - Front - Web

CONTACT

Location

Issy-Les-Moulineaux, FRANCE

Phone

+336.48.38.10.65

Email

cedric.hartland@gmail.com

Website

https://fr.linkedin.com/in/hartland

LANGUAGES

French

English



PERSONALITY



PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

PhD in computer science, passionate about software engineering and web development. I have past experience in AI (stochastic optimization, neural networks, machine learning), programming language and framework design.

I spent the past 4 years focusing on state of the art approaches toward developping front applications based on web technologies.

I am looking for an opportunity to adress new challenges that will require me to improve and expand my skills set.

EXPERIENCE

Since 2010 CAST

Senior Software Engineer, Scrum Master

Scrum master for 2+ years in teams of 6 to 10 - Paris & Bangalore

Technical lead - lead developer web services

lead developer & front-architect on 4 web applications

Software Developer, Internship supervisor

2009 - 2010 **EFREI**

Assistant Professor, Robotics Major Coordinator Research, Teaching, Administrative management

2005 - 2009 Université Paris Sud, CNRS, INRIA

PhD Candidate

Research, Internship supervision Temporary assistant professor position

Ecole Polytechnique

Teaching Assistant - evolutionary micro-robotics

EDUCATION

2005 - 2009 PhD in Computer Science

Université Paris Sud, CNRS, INRIA

Thesis in stochastic optimization, machine learning and neural networks

2004 - 2005 Master in Computer Science

Université Paris Sud

Since 2013 Trainings

Scrum, Management, Security (OWASP top 10)

SKILLS



Jasmine grunt coffeescript web components
Handlebars Selenium requirejs underscore
Handlebars Selenium requirejs jQuery API
GIT Javacc Scrum Backbonejs Karma NoSQL

Jenkins Junit SQL RESTfull Web Services data vizualization
Mocha Angularjs TDD Java html/5css3 highcharts UML

Angularjs TDD Javascript JEE MDA Bootstrap SVN

RESTfull Restrict Kanban Robotics
express Javascript JEE MDA Bootstrap SVN

Nodejs Artificial Intelligence

Design Patterns Data Mining Continous Integration
Big Data Machine Learning